<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2005-08-13T02:00:00.0000000+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;P&gt;Yesterday &lt;A href="http://www.planetkris.de"&gt;Christian&lt;/A&gt; and his girlfriend Mariana from Venezuela went to Leipzig on their road trip through Germany. I was happy giving both a place to&amp;nbsp;stay. Kris has also been a "Zivildienstleistender", a social service instead of joining the army after school. We got in contact after he was writing an article for the magazine that was delivered to each Zivi about once month IIRC. Since 1998 we stayed in touch by e-mail. As he's a real (and only) cyber-friend of mine, we first met in 2003 when he visited Leipzig for an &lt;A href="http://www.whatisultimate.com/"&gt;Ultimate&lt;/A&gt; tournament. Yesterday was the time of out second meeting.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I prepared &lt;A href="http://www.it99.org/axl/PermaLink,guid,f7e2610d-8a96-4fe3-a0cb-a015b7eb22b9.aspx"&gt;Aline's Noodles&lt;/A&gt; for them as they didn't have something well prepared for about four days. When &lt;A href="http://www.pixelplastic.de"&gt;Marci&lt;/A&gt; came back home we opened the bottle of wine they brought as a present. Later we went to "Besser Leben", which was crowded as always around 10:30 PM. The alternative was to check out "Schlechtes Versteck" here in Leipzig, Schleußig. We had nice conversations and a little bit too much of beer. In the end the whole company was really drunk, so the decision to leave for our beloved bed was easy to take. Kris was even in the state of taking a nap in the restroom and&amp;nbsp;on the floor afterwards.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Marci woke me at 8:30 when he finally left for his 60 day trip to Thailand, Myanmar and Cambodia. I wish him all the best for his journey!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;We got up at 11 this morning (with a little residual alcohol as expected) and started with a good breakfast. Afterwards we went to the city to see some of Leipzigs &lt;A href="http://www.gfzk.de"&gt;museums&lt;/A&gt; and architecture.&amp;nbsp;Unfortunately my knowledge of Leipzigs history and architecture is very shallow and I couldn't explain that&amp;nbsp;much. I think I'll have to work on that subject. Nevertheless, Mariana was pretty happy to see some of the artisan's work that make the city attractive (at least to me) and I hope she liked it.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;On our way back home we decided to visit the "Südvorstadt" where most of the student's life in L.E. takes place and see the beautiful buildings there. On our way we even were invited to a party.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Just for the record: The coffee count for Mariana reached its maximum today at five cups until they left. Of course she's got the chance to have more on their way to Dresden. :-)&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Thanks Kris and Mariana for your visit, I'll be happy to host you again. Hopefully I'll find time and money to visit Bordeaux!&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P class="nowPlaying"&gt;Now playing: &lt;A href="http://www.music-map.de/bugge+wesseltoft.html"&gt;Bugge Wesseltoft&lt;/A&gt; - Moving - Lone&lt;/P&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-08-13T21:58:36.3590000+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2005-09-20T23:47:10.2516560+02:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>611e53c3-87e1-40de-af7c-ff9291823b49</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Kris pays a visit</Title>
      <Categories>General</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>