<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2005-08-30T02:00:00.0000000+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;P&gt;After my exam (which went well) I didn't feel that good yesterday. I've had a queasy feeling in my stomach and the overall condition was a bit like a hangover (from &lt;A href="http://www.it99.org/axl/PermaLink,guid,6f524f64-39b1-4860-b97a-3034be1acd76.aspx"&gt;Saturday&lt;/A&gt;?).&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;In the evening I decided to call Robert, Steffi, Susi and Corinna for a little diversion at the &lt;A href="http://www.cospuden.de/"&gt;Cospuden lake&lt;/A&gt;. They agreed so I picked them up at their place and we drove heading south to the lake.&amp;nbsp;Although the sun was already setting and there were heaps of mosquitoes around we jumped into the water. It payed off since there was a really nice overview about the lake with an softly glowing sky in blue, orange and crimson. When&amp;nbsp;the giggling about the fun we had ceased the water soon became too cold. We got out to get dressed and drove back to Robert's place for a beer or two. I called Martin letting him know about our plans and&amp;nbsp;picked up him in Schleußig.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;When we&amp;nbsp;came back&amp;nbsp;Corinna&amp;nbsp;started giving Steffi a massage. This was like cinema for the rest of us as they had chosen to be placed directly in front of us. In the end everyone got a massage (I treated Robert's back) and I went to bed being more relaxed than ever. Thanks Steffi, I owe you something! :-)&lt;/P&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-08-30T13:29:23.7030000+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2007-02-12T21:42:32.2882500+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>d5fbfb65-fe42-4d9b-93a7-7da42095f144</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Yesterday evening</Title>
      <Categories>NonTech</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>