<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2005-08-17T02:00:00.0000000+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strike&gt;Today&lt;/strike&gt; (actually yesterday by now) Julia from Vienna, our first &lt;a href="http://www.hospitalityclub.org/"&gt;Hospitality Club&lt;/a&gt;
guest, left heading&amp;nbsp;to Cuba. She arrived on sunday and I was the
one to pick her up at the train station. In the evening we went to
Markus' birthday party which was nice as always. The next day I had a
pretty big hangover since I had too much of the good draught and other
things one might imagine. Julia was able to gather additional travel
information from Markus and Claudia which were in Cuba for about 3
weeks last year. She was even happy enough to&amp;nbsp;lend a travel book
from them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On monday she intentionally planned to leave Leipzig to catch her
flight to Cuba. At the airport she realized that due to some mistake in
her appointments book the flight was booked for sunday, the day she
arrived. Fortunately she got the chance to book another flight for only
99€ on wednesday, leaving from Frankfurt/Main. She went back from the
airport for another two days in Leipzig and&amp;nbsp;Martin and
I&amp;nbsp;welcomed her the second time. Due to some work on monday and
tuesday I didn't have the chance of showing her the city center so she
started exploring it on her own. I think she liked it pretty much as
she said she would like to move to Leipzig when she's got the chance to
live in Germany again. After all, we had two relaxing evenings with
nice conversation and well prepared meals. &lt;strike&gt;Today&lt;/strike&gt; (again, yesterday by now) at 6:30 she left to Halle to get her lift to FF/M. I hope she enjoyed her stay the same way we did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P class="now-playing"&gt;Now playing: &lt;a href="http://www.music-map.de/pelican+city.html"&gt;Pelican City&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;A href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000050ANG/therightstu0e-20"&gt;Rhode Island&lt;/a&gt; - The pier&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-08-18T00:40:40.3900000+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2007-02-12T21:42:41.0382500+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>79ce8c55-497c-4505-94cf-3d0ab58cfd51</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Julia</Title>
      <Categories>NonTech</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;P&gt;&lt;A href="http://pics.org.ua/poisk.html"&gt;Here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P class="now-playing"&gt;Now playing: &lt;A href="http://www.music-map.de/david+holmes.html"&gt;David Holmes&lt;/A&gt; -&amp;nbsp;Don't die just yet&lt;/P&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-08-17T19:49:06.5620000+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2006-01-29T15:56:48.2202254+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>c5b5013c-f468-4802-b13d-697d49d34133</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Find the three differences</Title>
      <Categories>Fun Stuff</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>