<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2005-08-28T02:00:00.0000000+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;P&gt;Every year at Whit sun me and&amp;nbsp;my friends are going to some place in Germany having a few days off in the country. This year we decided to go to Obergeißendorf where the summer house of my family is located. During the days there, Robert mentioned the great steak he ate at a restaurant. So we thought about preparing some of this kind of beef later this summer.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Yesterday evening we (Robert, Robert, Martin, Thomas and I) finally managed to meet at my place tasting&amp;nbsp;beef topped with herb butter,&amp;nbsp;baguette and&amp;nbsp;rocket salad. No doubt we also had beer and vodka. Robert bought a new barbecue set and plenty of meat: 2,85 kg of finest Brazilian steak for us five. This makes about 570 grams of beef for everyone. Knowing this, I didn't eat that much yesterday. It payed off,&amp;nbsp;but after my share of the cow I really felt stuffed. The &lt;A href="http://encyclopedia.thefreedictionary.com/Angostura+bitters"&gt;Angostura Bitter&lt;/A&gt; we all had to try afterward did a great job driving my digestion, although its taste was not remarkably good.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;The cozy part of the evening took place in&amp;nbsp;my room where we were listening to plenty of of tracks. Unfortunately, Robert was the one with the remote control to skip through my playlist after only 20 seconds of each song. We listened to about 90 percent of the songs this way, only 10 percent were allowed to be heard in their full beauty.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P class="now-playing"&gt;Now playing: Esbjörn Svensson Trio - &lt;A href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B0000APVCL/therightstu0e-20"&gt;E.S.T. Live 95&lt;/A&gt; - The rube thing&lt;/P&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-08-28T11:08:01.0460000+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2007-02-12T21:42:33.2882500+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>6f524f64-39b1-4860-b97a-3034be1acd76</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Brazilian Steak</Title>
      <Categories>NonTech</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>