<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2005-12-10T01:00:00.0000000+01:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;P&gt;Now that I am &lt;A href="http://bis.informatik.uni-leipzig.de/"&gt;at work&lt;/A&gt; most of the time I decided to give myself a pair headphones as an early Christmas present. Leipzig's &lt;A href="http://www.leipzig.de/de/buerger/freizeit/maerkte/weihnacht/"&gt;Weihnachtsmarkt&lt;/A&gt; which is located in front of my office was also a good reason buy these&amp;nbsp;because the "music" playing there the whole day long&amp;nbsp;and other sound pollution spreading around&amp;nbsp;is nothing but enervating to me.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I've done a little research online and then checked the local&amp;nbsp;Saturn store to see what they are offering. There I found a pair of &lt;A href="http://www.headphone.com/guide/by-manufacturer/beyerdynamic/beyerdynamic-dt-880.php"&gt;Beyerdynamic DT 880&lt;/A&gt; that were reduced from 250 €. The short sound check (Nothing else matters by&amp;nbsp;&lt;A href="http://www.music-map.de/metallica.html"&gt;Metallica&lt;/A&gt; played with a 50 Hz hum indicating bad grounding) inside the large store promised nothing special, so I decided to rely on the very good reviews by &lt;A href="http://www.audio.de/"&gt;Audio&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A href="http://www.stereo.de/"&gt;Stereo&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P align=center&gt;&lt;A href="http://www.it99.org/axl/content/binary/Beyerdynamic%20DT%20880.png" rel="lightbox"&gt;&lt;IMG alt="Beyerdynamic DT 880" src="http://www.it99.org/axl/content/binary/Beyerdynamic%20DT%20880%20small.png" border=0&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Back at work I connected the phones to my machine and was surprised. The bass is pleasantly heavy, mids and highs are presented very clear and clean. There's also a good spatial resolution. I often refer to "analytic" describing such presentation, which is the way I like to listen to music. The feeling of the phones surrounding the ear is very comfortable. No pressure marks, even after hours wearing them. The half-open headphone design allows listening to music at high volumes without disturbing&amp;nbsp;co-workers.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;You may ask why one should spend that much money just for headphones. At least, &lt;A href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/archives/000463.html"&gt;others&lt;/A&gt; to that.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;
&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Unlike your computer, or your car, your headphones will never wear out or become obsolete. I hesitate to say lifetime, but they're multiple decade investments at the very least.
&lt;LI&gt;The number one item that affects the music you hear is the speakers. Without a good set of headphones, everything else is irrelevant.
&lt;LI&gt;The right headphones can deliver sound equivalent to extremely high-end floorstanding speakers worth thousands of dollars.&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;I don't fully agree to point 3, but that's as always a matter of taste and how much you're into high fidelity. For you Hi-Fi enthusiasts, take a look at the &lt;A href="http://www.stax.co.jp/ENG/S-sys2E.html"&gt;Stax SRS-4040&lt;/A&gt;!&lt;/P&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2005-12-10T19:34:11.8750000+01:00</Created>
      <Modified>2005-12-10T19:48:52.0312500+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>664ce414-8cc7-4fe8-b4a0-18f52ca62f7b</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Beyerdynamic DT 880 Headphones</Title>
      <Categories>Hi-Fi</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>