<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2008-05-06T02:00:00+02:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;It's been a while: Sometime last August the SharePoint hosting contract for the &lt;a href="http://dotnet-leipzig.de/"&gt;.NET User Group Leipzig&lt;/a&gt; ran out and since then we basically didn't have an online presence. Our &lt;a href="http://dotnet-leipzig.de/summercamp/"&gt;.NET Summercamp 2007&lt;/a&gt; conference and a couple of smaller User Group events took away their share of spare time so I didn't find time to create our new home page. Over the last couple of months I evaluated several Content Management Systems for our to-be-developed homepage and what can I say, I was a bit disappointed. One CMS to remain unnamed showed very buggy behavior when setting up basic navigation elements and &lt;a href="http://www.dotnetnuke.com/"&gt;DotNetNuke&lt;/a&gt; had some scary CSS to override for custom layouts and uses tables all over the place.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Two months ago I came across telligent's &lt;a href="http://graffiticms.com/"&gt;Graffiti CMS&lt;/a&gt;. Delightful! They really appear to be driven by their &amp;quot;Content Made Simple&amp;quot; concept. Not only do they have a nice Ajax-y administration UI, Graffiti also provides an extremely simple and efficient &lt;a href="http://graffiticms.com/support/advanced-options/extending-chalk/"&gt;extensibility model&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://www.castleproject.org/others/nvelocity/index.html"&gt;NVelocity&lt;/a&gt; template engine is also very easy to grasp. (NVelocity is part of my beloved &lt;a href="http://www.castleproject.org/"&gt;Castle project&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;I started implementing some &lt;a href="http://graffiticms.com/support/advanced-options/chalk-overview/"&gt;macros&lt;/a&gt; for the User Group events, and soon it became clear that this might be something other User Groups might want to use as well. Thus, the open-source &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/graffiti-usergroups/"&gt;Graffiti-UserGroups&lt;/a&gt; project was born.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Basically &lt;a title="Torsten Weber" href="http://blogs.compactframework.de/Torsten.Weber/" rel="friend"&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; wanted to provide a list of recent and archived events with custom metadata and enable attendee registration. Speaking of metadata, this includes:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;a title="Event Detail" href="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Event.png" rel="lightbox"&gt;&lt;img alt="Event Detail" src="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Event-thumb.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Start and end dates      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;and time, optionally &lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Speaker &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Location      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;A default location should be set if no location was entered.&lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Maximum number of attendees (due to space limitations)      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;Again, a default maximum should be set if no value was given.&lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Registration recipient e-mail address      &lt;ul&gt;       &lt;li&gt;A default address should be used if no e-mail address was given. We sometimes host events in cooperation with the local &lt;a href="http://www.studentprogram.de/"&gt;Microsoft Student Partners&lt;/a&gt; (MSPs) so the address can change for MSP events. &lt;/li&gt;     &lt;/ul&gt;   &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This enables some neat use cases:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Registration for one or more events using a web form without needing to write an e-mail. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Automatic e-mails to the attendee and the event organizer. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;The notion of waiting lists for events that are booked up. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ICalendar"&gt;iCalendar&lt;/a&gt; item downloads for Outlook that are created based on the metadata above. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;a title="Registration Page" href="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Registration.png" rel="lightbox"&gt;&lt;img alt="Registration Page" src="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Registration-thumb.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;All functionality can be implemented using Graffiti's extensibility points, a &lt;a href="http://graffiticms.com/support/advanced-options/graffiti-events/"&gt;plug-in&lt;/a&gt; in this case. A plug-in can subscribe to certain events in the application, jump in and modify data (see default values above). Another extensibility point which is heavily used in &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/graffiti-usergroups/"&gt;Graffiti-UserGroups&lt;/a&gt; is the notion of &lt;a href="http://graffiticms.com/support/advanced-options/extending-chalk/"&gt;custom &amp;quot;Chalk&amp;quot; macros&lt;/a&gt; compiled into .NET assemblies. For example, there's a set of macros to display and format event data without the need to write complex &amp;quot;standard&amp;quot; Chalk statements.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;An extra bonus for the &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/graffiti-usergroups/"&gt;Graffiti-UserGroups&lt;/a&gt; newbie is the Demo Site Setup Wizard which configures your Graffiti site, including sample posts and a registration page. (Also see the video below where I demo the initial setup which is finished in minutes.)&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;a title="Demo Site Setup Wizard" href="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Demo-Site-Setup.png" rel="lightbox"&gt;&lt;img alt="Demo Site Setup Wizard" src="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Demo-Site-Setup-thumb.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;To make a long story short(er) I've recorded a screencast that shows you how to set up the demo site quickly on your local machine.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;a title="Click to watch video" href="http://www.therightstuff.de/download/Graffiti-UserGroups/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Click to watch video" src="http://www.therightstuff.de/content/binary/WindowsLiveWriter/Graffiti-UserGroups/Video.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Don't forget to take a look at the new &lt;a href="http://dotnet-leipzig.de/"&gt;.NET User Group Leipzig homepage&lt;/a&gt; to see the macros in action. Also check out the source code on &lt;a href="http://code.google.com/p/graffiti-usergroups/"&gt;Google Code&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2008-05-06T19:22:14.211+02:00</Created>
      <Modified>2008-05-06T20:26:02.6181114+02:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>81832312-c253-4921-83e9-573271fcb8a2</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Introducing Graffiti-UserGroups for Graffiti CMS</Title>
      <Categories>DNUG Leipzig;Graffiti CMS</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>false</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>