<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<DayEntry xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns="urn:newtelligence-com:dasblog:runtime:data">
  <Date>2010-01-17T01:00:00+01:00</Date>
  <Entries>
    <Entry>
      <Content>&lt;p&gt;After listening to the &lt;a href="http://hanselminutes.com/default.aspx?showID=209"&gt;Hanselminutes episode on Microsoft Solver Foundation&lt;/a&gt; (MSF) I decided it’s time to give it a shot today. Solver Foundation seems to be a solution to a set of constrained problems I sometimes face:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;   &lt;li&gt;Sharing costs and calculating minimal money transfers after trips with my friends, where each friend spent some money. &lt;/li&gt;    &lt;li&gt;Giving out questions to attendees of our &lt;a href="http://dotnet-leipzig.de/"&gt;User Group&lt;/a&gt; “Boot Camps”: Speakers prepare ~20 questions, ranging from easy to moderate levels. We assign each attendee an easy question and one to chew a bit upon. Further, every question should be given out to two attendees, so in case someone doesn’t make it to the meeting we’re still able to cover the question. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Something I don’t remember Scott Hanselman and his guest talking about is that Solver Foundation comes with an Excel Add-In that is supposed to make creating models &lt;strike&gt;easy&lt;/strike&gt; easier, no code needed. Along with the “Solver Foundation for Excel Primer” document that is installed along with the binaries I figured Excel would be a good way to start looking into Solver Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;After the MSI ran, I started Excel but didn’t find the Solver Foundation tab that’s advertised in the primer. The COM Add-Ins dialog said something about that the Add-In could not be loaded. Nice! Luckily the Event Viewer was more helpful in terms of error messages where I found &lt;a href="http://code.msdn.microsoft.com/solverfoundation/WorkItem/View.aspx?WorkItemId=37"&gt;this beauty of an exception&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;pre class="brush: text"&gt;Microsoft.VisualStudio.Tools.Applications.Runtime.CannotCreateCustomizationDomainException:
Customization could not be loaded because the application domain could not be created.
---&amp;gt; System.IO.FileLoadException: Could not load file or assembly 'MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel, Version=1.0.6.4890, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=31bf3856ad364e35' or one of its dependencies.
The located assembly's manifest definition does not match the assembly reference. (Exception from HRESULT: 0x80131040)&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first guess was that an old MSF assembly was referenced and I decided to go with an assembly binding redirect for excel.exe. Didn’t help. The next step was to get into the innards of VSTO deployment. What I found in the &lt;strong&gt;MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel.vsto&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel.dll.manifest&lt;/strong&gt; files wasn’t surpising: Several references to old versions of MSF. None of which were deployed by the MSI installer, so Excel trying to load such dependencies failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class="brush: xml"&gt;&amp;lt;assemblyIdentity name=&amp;quot;MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel&amp;quot; version=&amp;quot;1.0.8.6048&amp;quot;…
&amp;lt;assemblyIdentity name=&amp;quot;MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel&amp;quot; version=&amp;quot;1.0.6.4890&amp;quot;…&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I updated both references to the match the installed version 2.0.2.8632, just to find myself faced with another error saying that the manifest’s digital signature is broken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now was time to contact my friend &lt;a href="http://blog.lars-keller.net/" rel="met friend"&gt;Lars Keller&lt;/a&gt; who is an expert in VSTO development. Lars told me that I would have to re-sign the .vsto and .manifest files to make the signature reflect my changes. The Office Development with Visual Studio blog has the &lt;a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/vsto/archive/2009/04/29/signing-and-re-signing-manifests-in-clickonce.aspx"&gt;full details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I had to create a certificate that can be used for code signing: 
    &lt;pre  class="brush: shell"&gt;makecert -r -pe -n &amp;quot;CN=Your Name&amp;quot; -b 01/01/2010 -e 01/01/2099 -eku 1.3.6.1.5.5.7.3.3 -ss My&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Export the certificate as a PFX file using &lt;strong&gt;certmgr.msc&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Create a backup copy of the MSF Excel Add-In .manifest and .vsto files &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Open a Visual Studio Command prompt and navigate to the manifest's location &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Make edits to the manifest file correcting the assembly versions of MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel to 2.0.2.8632&lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Update the digital signatures for both the manifest and the VSTO file: 
    &lt;pre class="brush: shell"&gt;mage.exe -update MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel.dll.manifest -CertFile &amp;lt;your-cert.pfx&amp;gt; -Password &amp;lt;cert-export-password&amp;gt;
mage.exe -update MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel.vsto -appmanifest MicrosoftSolverFoundationForExcel.dll.manifest -CertFile &amp;lt;your-cert.pfx&amp;gt; -Password &amp;lt;cert-export-password&amp;gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Restart Excel, the Solver Foundation tab should be on the ribbon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Tested with Office 2010 beta.)&lt;/p&gt;</Content>
      <Created>2010-01-17T15:52:36.862+01:00</Created>
      <Modified>2010-01-18T00:19:04.612+01:00</Modified>
      <EntryId>9a2790dd-40bf-47ec-85be-6ada8f5da768</EntryId>
      <Description />
      <Title>Using the Microsoft Solver Foundation Add-In for Excel</Title>
      <Categories>.NET;Debugging;Office</Categories>
      <Author>agross</Author>
      <IsPublic>true</IsPublic>
      <Syndicated>true</Syndicated>
      <ShowOnFrontPage>true</ShowOnFrontPage>
      <AllowComments>true</AllowComments>
      <Attachments />
      <Crossposts />
      <Latitude xsi:nil="true" />
      <Longitude xsi:nil="true" />
    </Entry>
  </Entries>
</DayEntry>